export const TEXTILESA2021 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A fabric characterized by interlocking loops is produced by",
A: "braiding.",
B: "crocheting.",
C: "netting.",
D: "weaving.",
answer: "B. crocheting.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Three primary motions of a loom are",
A: "heddling, reeding and tie-up.",
B: "left off, pick up and take up.",
C: "shedding, picking and beat up.",
D: "take up, left off and pick up.",
answer: "C. shedding, picking and beat up.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The main purpose of spinning is to",
A: "blend different fibres.",
B: "make fibres lie parallel.",
C: "interlace yarns.",
D: "introduce twist fibres.",
answer: "D. introduce twist fibres.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Weaves are first designed on a point paper to",
A: "make the fibre last long.",
B: "make the loom ready for weaving.",
C: "obtain the required fabric.",
D: "obtain the required structure.",
answer: "D. obtain the required structure.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The traditional hand spindle turns by rotating the",
A: "notch.",
B: "pulley.",
C: "sley.",
D: "Whorl.",
answer: "D. Whorl.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. During dyeing, it is extremely important to keep the fabric submerged in the dye solution to avoid",
A: "bleeding.",
B: "fading.",
C: "over dyeing,",
D: "patchy effect.",
answer: "D. patchy effect.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. A technique in which motifs are drawn on plain cloth and stitched using coloured threads is",
A: "appliqué.",
B: "crocheting.",
C: "embroidery.",
D: "tapestry.",
answer: "C. embroidery.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The final product from cellulose xanthate is",
A: "cotton.",
B: "rayon.",
C: "silk.",
D: "wool.",
answer: "B. rayon.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The smell of paper during burning test identifies",
A: "cotton fibre.",
B: "nylon fibre.",
C: "silk fibre.",
D: "wool fibre.",
answer: "A. cotton fibre.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The short fibres of cotton are referred to as",
A: "fluffs.",
B: "lints.",
C: "tows.",
D: "wastes.",
answer: "B. lints.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The formation of /euco compound is associated with",
A: "direct dyeing.",
B: "naphtol dyeing.",
C: "reactive dyeing.",
D: "vat dyeing.",
answer: "D. vat dyeing.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Satin weave fabrics can be identified by",
A: "diagonal lines.",
B: "loops on the surface.",
C: "lustrous appearance.",
D: "it’s compactness.",
answer: "C. lustrous appearance.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The best way to remove starch paste from a dyed resist fabric is by",
A: "applying chemicals.",
B: "dipping the fabric in hot water.",
C: "scrubbing and washing.",
D: "ironing the fabric.",
answer: "B. dipping the fabric in hot water.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Select the finishing technique that creates fluffy appearance on a fabric.",
A: "Calendaring",
B: "Napping",
C: "Singeing",
D: "Stentering",
answer: "B. Napping",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following methods can be used to show the difference between linen and cotton?",
A: "Burning test",
B: "Chemical test",
C: "Microscopic examination",
D: "Physical examination",
answer: "C. Microscopic examination",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Identify the agency that may provide financial assistance for a textile entrepreneur.",
A: "Centre for National Culture",
B: "Council for Scientific and Industrial Research",
C: "Ghanaian Association of Visual Artists",
D: "National Board for Small Scale Industry",
answer: "D. National Board for Small Scale Industry",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A reason for observing healthy studio practices is to prevent",
A: "collection of chemicals.",
B: "destruction of chemicals.",
C: "distribution of chemicals.",
D: "inhalation of chemicals.",
answer: "D. inhalation of chemicals.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The process of spinning yarn traditionally is by using the",
A: "mule,",
B: "ring machine.",
C: "roving machine.",
D: "tighs.",
answer: "D. thighs.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The base for cellolosic fibre is",
A: "chemical.",
B: "protein.",
C: "regenerated.",
D: "vegetable.",
answer: "D. vegetable.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. One way of sustaining Ghana’s indigenous textile industry is to",
A: "preserve the natural resources.",
B: "invite foreign textile artists.",
C: "import most of the textile products.",
D: "clear cotton plantations for factories.",
answer: "A. preserve the natural resources.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Identify the reason why caustic soda must be dissolved in cold water.",
A: "Avoidance of explosion",
B: "Avoidance of oxidation",
C: "Prevention of inhalation",
D: "Prevention of suffocation",
answer: "A. Avoidance of explosion",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The foremost important factor to consider when preparing for an exhibition is the",
A: "preparation of brochures.",
B: "provision of refreshment.",
C: "space in the hall.",
D: "total cost involved.",
answer: "C. space in the hall.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. A business plan in textiles",
A: "describes production activities.",
B: "monitors human rights.",
C: "monitors individual worker.",
D: "satisfies individual worker.",
answer: "A. describes production activities.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. To break even means that production cost is equal to the",
A: "cost price.",
B: "profit margin.",
C: "selling price.",
D: "variable cost.",
answer: "C. selling price.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Acomponent of the price of a textile product is the cost of",
A: "fuel.",
B: "labour.",
C: "materials and wages.",
D: "products from other companies.",
answer: "C. materials and wages.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Calculate the ends needed to weave a piece of fabric 30 cm wide using a reed of 24 dents per centimetre.",
A: "54 ends",
B: "60 ends",
C: "125 ends",
D: "720 ends",
answer: "D. 720 ends",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. A trait that should be exhibited by a textile artist is",
A: "honesty.",
B: "patriotism.",
C: "philanthropy.",
D: "sympathy.",
answer: "A. honesty.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Tie-dye and printing are classified under fabric",
A: "construction.",
B: "decoration.",
C: "exploration.",
D: "preparation.",
answer: "B. decoration.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. During beaming, the raddle is used to",
A: "assist the reed.",
B: "make heddling easier.",
C: "roll the warp.",
D: "spread the warp ends.",
answer: "D. spread the warp ends.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Choose from the options, the statement that best describes colour.",
A: "Absorbed light on objects",
B: "Diffused light from objects",
C: "Refracted light on objects",
D: "Reflected light from objects",
answer: "D. Reflected light from objects",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Veinal effect in batik making is achieved by",
A: "cracking wax.",
B: "painting with wax.",
C: "stamping the wax.",
D: "removing wax.",
answer: "A. cracking wax.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Which type of dyestuff shows the true colour after oxidation?",
A: "Azoic dye",
B: "Pigment dye",
C: "Reactive dye",
D: "Vat dye",
answer: "D. Vat dye",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Identify a pile fabric from the options.",
A: "Calico",
B: "Khaki",
C: "Poplin",
D: "Towel",
answer: "D. Towel",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Identify the pair that is a direct cost in an enterprise.",
A: "Overhead and profit",
B: "Raw materials and labour",
C: "Salaries and wages",
D: "Transport and communication",
answer: "B. Raw materials and labour",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The finishing process applied to cotton fabrics to prevent shrinkage is",
A: "calendaring.",
B: "mercerization.",
C: "sanforization.",
D: "tentering.",
answer: "C. sanforization.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Identify a resist dyeing technique from the options.",
A: "Embroidering",
B: "Knotting",
C: "Lacquering",
D: "Printing",
answer: "B. Knotting",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. When an even shade is obtained after dyeing, it is termed",
A: "concentrated dyeing.",
B: "fast dyeing.",
C: "level dyeing.",
D: "short dyeing.",
answer: "C. level dyeing.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Select from the options, the two major classes of dye.",
A: "Cold and hot",
B: "Synthetic and natural",
C: "Vat and basic",
D: "Vegetable and mineral",
answer: "B. Synthetic and natural",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Crumpling is a technique in tie-dyeing which creates",
A: "a marbled effect.",
B: "circular effect.",
C: "triangular effect.",
D: "zigzag effect.",
answer: "A. a marbled effect.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. An example of mercerized cotton fabric is",
A: "greybaft.",
B: "khaki.",
C: "polyester.",
D: "poplin.",
answer: "D. poplin.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]